<idea-plugin>
    <id>pl.artoledev.dependencyupdater</id>
    <name>DependencyUpdater</name>
    <vendor email="artur.olejniczak.dev@gmail.com" > Artur Olejniczak</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
      <h3>The ultimate dependency manager and security scanner for IntelliJ IDEA</h3>
      <p><b>DependencyUpdater</b> is a powerful plugin designed explicitly for <b>Maven</b> and <b>Gradle</b> projects. 
      It acts as your intelligent assistant to keep your build files clean, updated, and secure.</p>
      
      <h4>Key Features:</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>🚀 <b>Full Maven & Gradle Support:</b> Seamlessly parses <code>pom.xml</code> and <code>build.gradle / build.gradle.kts</code> files.</li>
        <li>🛡️ <b>Security Scanning (OSV API):</b> Automatically detects Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) in your direct and <b>transitive</b> dependencies.</li>
        <li>🔄 <b>Smart Version Updates:</b> Discovers newer library versions directly from your configured artifact repositories.</li>
        <li>🔐 <b>Custom Repositories:</b> Connects to private registries (like JFrog Artifactory) with safe Bearer Token and Basic authentication.</li>
        <li>🎯 <b>LTS Filtering:</b> Highlights Long Term Support (LTS) releases for safer enterprise upgrades.</li>
      </ul>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
      <b>Version 1.2</b>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Custom Repositories:</b> Added a new Settings page to manage multiple custom artifact repositories.</li>
        <li><b>Secure Authentication:</b> Full support for Basic (Username/Password) and Bearer Token authentication via IntelliJ PasswordSafe.</li>
        <li><b>Concurrent Fetching:</b> The plugin now queries all configured repositories simultaneously to fetch the latest dependency versions.</li>
      </ul>
      <br>
      <b>Version 1.1</b>
      <ul>
        <li><b>IDE Compatibility:</b> Updated to support IntelliJ IDEA 2026.1 and fixed deprecated <code>FilenameIndex</code> API usages.</li>
        <li><b>Marketplace Compliance:</b> Updated plugin ID and configured proper <code>untilBuild</code> limits.</li>
        <li><b>Code Quality:</b> Refactored codebase, removed unused comments, and bumped Gradle Wrapper to 9.5.1 with updated Mockito framework.</li>
      </ul>
      <br>
      <b>Version 1.0</b>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Initial Release:</b> Scans Maven and Gradle projects for outdated dependencies.</li>
        <li><b>Security Scanning:</b> Integrates with OSV API to expose Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) for direct and transitive dependencies.</li>
        <li><b>LTS Filtering:</b> Highlights Long Term Support versions for safer upgrades.</li>
      </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <!-- Dependencies on other plugins (to access Maven and Java PSI structures) -->
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.java</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.idea.maven</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.plugins.gradle</depends>

    <!-- Extension declarations (Tool windows, actions, services) -->
    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <applicationService serviceImplementation="com.example.dependencyupdater.settings.DependencyUpdaterSettingsState"/>
        <applicationConfigurable parentId="tools" instance="com.example.dependencyupdater.settings.DependencyUpdaterSettingsConfigurable" id="com.example.dependencyupdater.settings.DependencyUpdaterSettingsConfigurable" displayName="Dependency Updater"/>
        
        <!-- Registering our Tool Window -->
        <toolWindow id="Dependency Updater" 
                    secondary="true" 
                    anchor="bottom" 
                    icon="AllIcons.General.Warning"
                    factoryClass="com.example.dependencyupdater.DependencyUpdaterToolWindowFactory"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <!-- Top menu actions can be added here in the future -->
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
